<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OOP on</title><link>https://arkamfahry.github.io/quartz/tags/OOP/</link><description>Recent content in OOP on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://arkamfahry.github.io/quartz/tags/OOP/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Class and Object</title><link>https://arkamfahry.github.io/quartz/Nibm_Notes/OOP/Concepts/class_and_object/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkamfahry.github.io/quartz/Nibm_Notes/OOP/Concepts/class_and_object/</guid><description>Class A class is a template (blueprint) which is used to create objects in programming
A class has attributes and functions</description></item><item><title>Encapsulation</title><link>https://arkamfahry.github.io/quartz/Nibm_Notes/OOP/Concepts/encapculation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkamfahry.github.io/quartz/Nibm_Notes/OOP/Concepts/encapculation/</guid><description>Encapsulation is the process of combining Attributes and Methods in to single unit.
The basic unit of encapsulation is the class.</description></item><item><title>Java</title><link>https://arkamfahry.github.io/quartz/Nibm_Notes/OOP/Java/java/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkamfahry.github.io/quartz/Nibm_Notes/OOP/Java/java/</guid><description>Install Java JDK Side note need an oracle account Install java version 8 for stability Install java in the default location Install all the default development tools Set the environment variables for java and javac Facts about java Java is a compiled and interpreted programing language which runs on more then 3 billion devices Java is used to build app for mobile application to enterprise scale server application Java is a statically typed language with garbage collection Java is also case sensitive Java compiler (Javac) The Java compiler (javac) is the compiler which turns java source code into class files which contains java bytecode which is run on the Java virtual machine (JVM) Java virtual machine (JVM) Java virtual machine is used to execute the java byte code which are in java class files Java virtual machine is a abstract virtual machine that runs on top of the host OS.</description></item></channel></rss>